Quang Hien LE

Molecular Geneticist & Computational Biologist

Leads the development of a bioinformatics platform.

With research experience in plant genomics, provides scientific support for the analysis of biological data & builds collaborative projects involving inter-disciplinary teams. Open-minded technology enthusiast, looks for new challenges.



Experience

2008-(...) Bioanalysis & bioinformatics

Limagrain Vegetable Seeds, Chappes France

- Manage a bioinformatics & bioanalysis team
- Develop a bioinformatics computing platform
- Provide scientific, technical & strategic counsel

Oct. 2008 Freelance Consultant

Centre d'Analyse Stratégique, Paris France

• Advise on the future of genetics & genomics

2006-2008 Research Engineer

CNRS UPVD/IRD, Perpignan France

• Bioinformatic analysis of transposons

2004-2006 Post-doc

GDPP, INRA Bordeaux France

• Map a gene for potyvirus resistance

2002-2004 Post-doc

IJPB, INRA Versailles France

• Impact of transposons on genome evolution

1997-2002 Ph.D. candidate

McGill University, Montreal Canada

• Characterize transposons & their mobility

Winter 2001 Teaching Assistant

McGill University, Montreal Canada

• Cell & Molecular Biology (undergraduate)

1994-1996 M.Sc. Intern

Université de Montréal, Canada

- Study the circadian clock in a dinoflagellate
- Develop of a biolistic protocol for micro-algae

Education

1997-2002 Ph.D. Biology, Dean's Honour List

McGill University, Montreal, Canada

Aug. 1999 Canadian Bioinformatics Workshop

University of Calgary, Canada

1994-1996 M.Sc. Molecular Biology

Université de Montréal, Canada

1991-1994 B.Sc. Biology

Université de Montréal, Canada

1984-1991 Collège Jean-de-Brébeuf

Montreal, Canada

Contact

Clermont-Ferrand, France

+33.637.466.426

+33.611.745.912

Mien@wetbench.eu

www.wetbench.eu/cv

in linkedin.com/in/qhienle

Skills

Computational

Bioinformatics

Perl

Python

SQL

Bash

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Biology

Genomics

Transcriptomics

Genetics

Molecular Biology

Sequencing

Comparative Genomics

Molecular Cloning

Languages

French

English

Vietnamese

Honours & Awards

McGill Dean's Honour List Bourse Haigneré (INRA) Bourse NATEQ (Québec) McGill Major Fellowships Canada Scholarship

Quang Hien LE

Molecular Geneticist & Computational Biologist

Clermont-Ferrand, France

+33.637.466.426

+33.611.745.912

★ hien@wetbench.eu

www.wetbench.eu/cv

in linkedin.com/in/qhienle

Other activities

Achievements

- 1st prize, high school literary contest
 (Lis-tes-ratures), illustrated story category
- 1st dan (black belt) Aikido
- Blue belt Traditional Vietnamese Martial Arts (Sa Long Cuong)

Hobbies

- Cycling, snowboarding, hiking, martial arts, drawing, comic books, guitar
- Author of http://wetbench.blogspot.com
- Amateur photography, Instagram, Flickr (follow *qhienle*)
- Parenting

List of Publications

Peer reviewed

http://wetbench.eu/cv/index.html#publications

Past involvements

- Urban cyclist, member of the associations:
 - + Vélo-Cite 63 (velocite63.net) &
 - + Vélo-en-Têt (veloentet.free.fr).
- Designs & illustrations for posters, T-shirts, school & community newspapers, newsletters, web sites
- Representative for Non-Permanents, INRA-Versailles Unit Council
- Pack leader, Vietnamese Secular Boy Scouts
- Social work for the Vietnamese community of Montreal
- Volunteer for the Association des femmes vietnamiennes de Montréal